Guide to the Virginia Gardner Papers TAM 100
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
- Series IV: Journalism Career
  - Subseries IV:E: New York employment
    - Newspaper article by VG on "Cotton Picking,", undated (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Newspaper article by VG on "Cotton Picking," John Rankin, Congressman, undated (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Correspondence: From VG regarding employment status at an Unidentified newspaper, undated (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Notes and rewrite of story by VG on, "Veteran Telegrapher", undated (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Press Release regarding Talk Show by VG, undated (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Speeches by VG, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 73)
- Series V: Correspondence Addendum
  - Correspondence - to be integrated, undated (Box 4, Folder 0.1)
  - Correspondence - to be integrated, undated (Box 4, Folder 0.2)
  - Correspondence, 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Series VI: Research
  - Subseries VI:A: Friend and Lover(Research Files, Typescript)
    - Appendix, undated (Folder 10)
    - Book outline, undated (Folder 11)
    - Book party invite, undated (Folder 12)
    - Book proposal, undated (Folder 13)
    - Caption material, undated (Folder 14)
    - Chapter 2, undated (Folder 15)
    - Chapter 4, undated (Folder 16)
    - Chapter 5, undated (Folder 17)
    - Chapter 6, undated (Folder 18)
    - Chapter 7, undated (Folder 19)
    - Chapter 8, undated (Folder 20)
    - Chapter 10, undated (Folder 21)
    - Chapter 11, undated (Folder 22)
    - Chapter 12, undated (Folder 23)
    - Chapter 12 - research, undated (Folder 24)
    - Chapter 13, undated (Folder 25)
    - Chapter 14; Chapter 14 - Portland newspaper clippings, undated (Folder 26)
    - Chapter 15, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Chapter 15 - research, undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Chapter 16, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Chapter 18 - research, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Chapter 21, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Chapter 25, undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Copyright, undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Corrigenda, undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Epilogue, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Memos (misc.), undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - B. Research Files, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Abbot, Berenice, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Aiken, Conrad, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Alexander, Doris, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Anderson, Sherwood, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Andreychin, George, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Anthony, Katherine, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Ashleigh, Charles, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Baldwin, Roger, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Barnes, Djuna; Oct. 1971, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Barnett, Ernesta (Bullitt), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Bavid, Peggy, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Belden, Harry, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Bell Syndicate, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Berkman, Alexander to Louise Bryant, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Biddle, George, 1969-1973 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Boardman, Robinson to Louise Bryant, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Bohlen, Charles, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Bome, Margaret, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Boni, Albert, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Bonus March, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Boulton, Agnes, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Bowers, Claude, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Boyer, William, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Boyle, Kay, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Bradley, Ruth interviewed by Julia Ruuttila; May-1970, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Brown, Susan Jenkins, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Brest-Litovsk, peace of, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Bryant Floyd Sherman, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Bryant, Louise - 1922 series, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Bryant, Louise - bibliography, undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Bryant, Louise "Fables for Proletarian Children," (The Revolutionary Age, Jan 25, p. 6), 1919 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Bryant, Louise - last years, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Bryant, Louise - Mirrors of Moscow. Reviews, undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Bryant, Louise - newspaper clippings, undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Bryant, Louise - obituaries, undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Bryant, Louise - Six Months in Russia. Reviews, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Bryant, Louise - speeches, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Bryant, Louise to William Bullitt, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Bryant, Louise to Anne Dennis Bursch, undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Bryant, Louise to Claude McKay, undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Bryant, Louise to John Reed in hospital, undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Bryant/Reed marriage certificate, undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Bryant, Sheridan L., undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Bullitt, Anne, undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Bullitt, Orville, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Bullitt, William C., undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - California background 1800s, undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Cameron, Angus, undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Campbell, Marguerite interview; 27-Aug-1970, undated (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Cannell, Kathleen, undated (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Cannon, Myra L. interviewed by Juliaa Ruuttila, 1970/1977 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Carroll, Frances interviewed by Juliaa Ruuttila; Jun/Jul 1970, undated (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Cemeteries, undated (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Chi Omega/Psi Alpha Chapter, undated (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Churchill, Allen. The Improper Bohmeian. (notes), undated (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Cole, Lester, undated (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Colum, Padriac, undated (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Cowl, Carl, undated (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Cowley, Malcom, undated (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Crichton, Linley interviewed by Virginia Gardner; Apr-1971, undated (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Dasburg, Alfred and Ann, 1975-1982 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Dasburg, Andrew, undated (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Dasburg, Mabel, undated (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Day, Dorothy, undated (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Day, Dorothy. On Pilgrimage (typescript, 34pp.), undated (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Dee, Ivan, 1973-1982 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - d'Anunzio, Gabriele, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Dell, Floyd, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Dietrich, Christopher, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Draper, Theodore, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Drinker Bower, Catherine, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Drinnon, Richard, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Dubrow, Elridge, interviewed by Virginia Gardner, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Duncan, Isadora, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Dunn, Robert W., undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Dyer, Madelin, interview, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Eastman, Max, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Ehrgott, Albert, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Elwyn, Frances interviewed by Virginia Gardner, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Emancipation of women and the revolution, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Equi, Marie, 1970, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Eudey, Elizabeth, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Failing, Henrietta interviewed by Julia Ruuttila; Dec-1970, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Everest, Wesley, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Feldenheimer (sculpture); May-1970, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Fenton, Lela Goddard; Apr-1970, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Field, Sara Bard to Louise Bryant (Note: this folder has been integrated into box 8, folder 22: Wood, Sara Bard Field), 1922 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Finger, Avram, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Finnish comrades to Louise Bryant, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Fischer, Louis, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Flanner, Janet, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Flick/Say families, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Frasier, Brownell D., undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Freud, Anna, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Gardner, Virginia, "John Reed and Lenin: some Insights based on Mss. Collection at Harvard", (Science and Society, 388-403); Fall 1967, undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - George, Juillette, undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Gold, Michael, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Goldman, Emma, undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Gorki, Maxim, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Greene, Bill, undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Groton map, undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Hair, Mozelle interview, undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Hamblet, Millie Hunewill, undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Hartwell, Mortimer Mrs., undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Hicks, Granville, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Hovey, Tamara Gold, undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Hug, George Mrs. interviewed by Juliaa Ruuttila; Jun-1970, undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Hunkins, Hallinan Hazal, undated (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Interviews, undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Irving, Leila (Borchers), interviewed by Juliaa Ruuttila, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Jenkins, Mrs. Frank and Olive Vinton, interviewed by Juliaa Ruuttila; Jun/Jul 1970, undated (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Judson, W. to Louise Bryant, undated (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Kemal Pasha, undated (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Kern, Grace interview, undated (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Kogan, Herman, undated (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Kollontai, Alexandra, undated (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Krupskaya, N. interviewed by Louise Bryant, undated (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Kuntz, Charles, undated (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Lahey, Edwin, undated (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Lamont, Charles, undated (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Larkin, Jim case - trial and sentence, covered by Louise Bryant, undated (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Lenin research notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Luhan, Mabel Dodge, undated (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Macmickle, Emilie Muhr interview; Jun/Jul 1970, undated (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - Maguire, Molly, undated (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - Mack, Theresa (Tessa); Jun-1970, undated (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Marx quotes, undated (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - Masses, Trial, the, undated (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - McCay, Claude, undated (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - Meeropol, Elli and Beth, undated (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - Meyendorff, Sasha, undated (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - Miners/Labor, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 67)
    - Mohan, Hugh J., undated (Box 6, Folder 68)
    - Mohan, Louisa, undated (Box 6, Folder 69)
    - Moore, Lucia, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Mussolini - Louise Bryant on, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Myers, Ethel Barnard and Horton Nicholas, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Nevada, University of, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Nizer - correspondence, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Nizer - court documents, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Nizer - court documents, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Nizer - lists of comparison, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Nizer - newspaper clippings, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - (No Desc.), undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Oliphant, Elizabeth interview; May-1970 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Oregon first families, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Overman Committee hearing, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Parker, Margaret; Feb-1971, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Parsons, Elsie Clews, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Parsons, Geoffrey, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Pearce, Charles, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Portland, OR, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Portland, OR - John Reed Centennial, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Portland newspaper on Bryant-Bullitt marriage, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Powell, Alice, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Powers, Alfred; Nov-1970, undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Provincetown interviews, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Putnam, Sam, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Psychological approach to Bullitt - notes on conversation, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Rabinowitz Foundatioin, undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Ramp, Floyd interview, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Reds Virginia Gardner on the film, undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Reed, John - copies of transcript, undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Reed, John - death, undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Reed, John - family, undated (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Reed, John in Harvard, undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Reed, John - newspaper clippings, undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Reed, John - photographs, undated (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Reed, John - poems, undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Reed, John to Louise Bryant, undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Reed, John to Louise Bryant, 1917 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Reed, John to Louise Bryant, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Reed, John - letters to and from Louise Bryant in Paris, undated (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Reed, John to Steffens, undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Reed, Margaret, undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Reed, Margaret to Louise Bryant, undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Reed, Margaret to John Reed after Louise's departure (speaking tour?), undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Reed Memorial meeting, 1921 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Research notes misc., undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Richmond, Al, undated (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Riverwood House (Paul and Louise), undated (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Robins, Raymond, undated (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Rogers, Bobby to Louise Bryant, undated (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Rosenstone, Robert, 1970-1976 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Root case correspondence, undated (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Russia misc., undated (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Russian revolution, undated (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Ruuttila, Juliaa Kathleen, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Ruuttila, Juliaa Kathleen, 1971-1974 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - San Martin, Nancy, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Sanger, Margaret (Godman), undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Seldes, George, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Sheaffer, Louis, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Sheean, Vincent, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Shirer, William L., undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Smith Miller, Leslie interview; Jul-1970, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Steffens, Lincoln, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Stoller, Leo, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Stone, Judy, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Suffrage, Oregon, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Strong, Anna Louise, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Thomas, Mura Dehn, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Trask, Williard R., undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Trotzky, Leon, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Trullinger, Louise, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Trullinger, Paul, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Velodarsky- Civil War, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Voice of Labor notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Walsh, Frank, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Washburne, Claude, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - William, Albert Rhys. Legionnaire (typescript, 19 pp.), undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - William, Albert Rhys. Journey into Revolution, 1917-1918 notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Winter, Ella, 1971, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Wood, Sara Bard Field, undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Wood, Erskine, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Zinoviev, undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Subseries VI:B: The Rosenberg Story (Research Files)
    - National Committee to Reopen the Rosenberg Case, 1985-1988 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Sobell-case newspaper clippings, undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Rosenberg sons, articles about, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Rosenberg case - newspaper clippings (unsorted), 1953-1956, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Reuben, William A., To Secure Justice in the Rosenberg Case (pamphlet, 31 pp.); ca., ca.1951 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Pamphlet: An appeal to President Dwight D. Eisenhower to spare the lives of Julius and Ethel Rosenberg; ca., ca.1953 (Box 8, Folder 34)
- Series VII: Unprocessed Materials
  - Unprocessed Materials (Box 3A)
  - Unprocessed Materials (Box 9-11)